Abylay Aiyp

Junior SWE with 1-year enterprise experience in front-end development using React. Built smaller projects using Spring MVC (Java) and PostgreSQL. Eager to join the company to build innovative and stable business solutions for its clients. My main goals are to write code, make design decisions, contribute to the company culture and learn more.

EXPERIENCE

SULU DAR, Nur-Sultan— Front-end Developer

July 2021 - PRESENT 2021

Web services for the convenience of creating entries in the salon

- Created two complex web applications using advanced front-end technologies
- Integrated back-end queries considering the best performance

Gefest Studio, Almaty — Web Developer

July 2021 - December 2021

Full-stack software development agency. Builds web and mobile applications for clients.

- Created a simple but powerful layout for 2 websites (Olevi, Lucem) that front-end developers based their work on
- Integrated showing list of products with back-end with minimal guidance from senior engineer

Human Touch, Remote — QA

January 2021 - April 2021

Human Touch is a US-based startup and a mobile application for video communication with customers for premium brands.

- Conducted manual testing according to a given scenario
- Identified application bugs and discussed problems with developers
- Tested a mobile application for the iOS platform

PROJECTS

Olevi — *E*-commerce website

A company in the field of food distribution under its own brand name Olevi.

- Created React components for 4 pages from Figma templates.
 Developed filter functionality for the catalog page.
 [React, Tailwind CSS]
- Integrated showing list of products with back-end with minimal guidance from senior engineer

Nur-Sultan, Kazakhstan +7 (747) 978-9144 ablyaip@gmail.com https://github.com/abylaip https://gitlab.com/abylaip

SKILLS

Advanced:

JavaScript, React, NextJS
HTML/CSS, Tailwind CSS

Intermediate:

Java (Spring) C++ PostgreSQL Git

AWARDS

INFOMATRIX - 2019
International IT projects competition.
Won a silver medal in the computer programming category with a mobile application project to help people with cardiovascular diseases.

LANGUAGES

Kazakh native Russian native English advanced

EDUCATION

Astana IT University Nur-Sultan, Kazakhstan B.S. in Software Engineering September 2020 - PRESENT

Lucem — Polyclinic web-service

An upcoming centralized web-service to make an appointment for many medical services.

 Created React components of the client and administrative side from Figma templates and integrated back-end queries.
 [React, Tailwind CSS, GraphQL]

Sulu CRM/Admin — Appointment creation web services

Web-services to make an appointment for salon services

- Created all layouts and functionality of all pages based on Figma [React, Tailwind CSS]
- Integrated back-end queries considering the best performance [Insomia, axios]